Guide to the Elaine D. Engst papers, 1979-2015.
Engst, Elaine D. papers
- Utopia Steering Committee and the Machine-Readable Cataloging (MARC) Mapping Project, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Utopia Data Field Overview, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Archives and Historical Documentation Program, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Archivist/Records Manager Employment, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Transcripts of Donald Smith Interviews with Graduates from the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- The Vicos Collection and the Cornell-Peru Project, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- The United States of American Vietnam War Commemoration Objectives, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Exhibit Cards and Items List for Vietnam War Exhibit, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Donor Instructions for the Vietnam War Veterans Archives, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Standards for Accessibility of Archival Visual Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Task Force on Digital Technology and Visual Images, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Helene Wastl's Admission to the Cornell University Graduate School, 1934-1935, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Wave Hill and the Catalog of Landscape Records in the United States, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant Application for the Witchcraft Collection, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
- The Andrew Dickson White Collection of Architectural Photographs
  - The Andrew Dickson White Collection of Architectural Photographs and the Delmas Foundation, 1999, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Digitization of the Andrew Dickson White/College of Architecture Photographs Collection with Reports, 1992, 1997-1998, 2000, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 40-41)
  - Helen Magill White Papers (Includes photocopies), 1871, 1951, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Items on Professor Burt Green Wilder and the Wilder Brain Collection (Includes photocopies), 1890, 1893, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 43)
- The Eastern Wine and Grape Archive
  - Documentary Heritage Program (DHP) Grant Applications for Grape Growing and Wine Making in New York State: A Regional Documentation Planning Initiative, 1947, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 44-48)
  - "Grapes of Wrath," by Kari R. Smith, in Empire State Report, 2003, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - "The Wines of New York State" and Eastern Wine and Grape Archive Brochures, 2004, 2006, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Items on Winter Activities and Weather at Cornell University for Presentations, 1949, 1999, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Joan M. Winters Correspondence and the Winters Frost Andrews Conklin Fund, 1997, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  Includes 21 Color Photographs
- Women's History at Cornell University
  - List of Women Students at Cornell University from 1872 to 1888, c. 2006 (Box 8, Folder 53-54)
  - Draft of "An Intitution where Women are Persons," Co-Authored by Carol Kammen, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Sage College Exhibit Planning (Includes photocopies), 1867-1868, 1892, 1990, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 56-57)
  - List of Women Faculty at Cornell University until 1974, 1974, 1996, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Report of the Women's Medical Office from September 22, 1934 to June 15, 1935, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - "Doing Women's History: A Conference on Research Sources at Cornell" and Bibliographies of Women's History Sources, 1984-1987, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 60-62)
    Folder 8-62 Includes 7 Photographs
- Woodland Cultural Centre Visit to Cornell University, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 63)
- Paul Yamauchi's Loan of the Sherman and Georgia Leland Letters, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 64)
- "Pink Slips" and Item Lists for Classes and Presentations
  - History 418 - Comparative Agrarian History: Peasants, Politics and History, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Asian American Studies 480 - Comparing Regimes of Race Control: A Seminar, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "The Situation in the Balkans from October, 1912, to October, 1913: An Address by President Schurman", 1913 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - List of Civil War Collections and Call Numbers, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Society for the Humanities 419/History 427/Spanish Literature 421 - Spatial Histories of Latin America, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - List of Natural Science Illustration Manuscripts and History of Geology Collections, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - History 1173 - Understanding the Past: Exploring Earlier Examples of Collection and Display, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - City and Regional Planning - The Regional City: Polycentric Metropolitan Areas in the U.S., Italy, and Netherlands, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Rural Sociology 615 (and 630/694) - Qualitative Research Methods, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - History 246/Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies 241 - New York Women, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Willard D. Straight Class, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Travel Class, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Telegraph Class, 2001, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - History/American Studies/Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies 4141 - Women's Activism and Social Change in the Twentieth Century United States, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Women Landscape Architects Class, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Classes and Presentations (Includes photocopies), 1864, 1994, 1998-1999, 2001, 2003-2005, 2007, 2011-2012 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
  - Newspaper Articles on "Remembering Cornell" Exhibition, the 130th Anniversary of Cornell University, and President Frank H. T. Rhodes, 1977, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Photographs for the "Remembering Cornell" Exhibition and Program, 1995, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Event Planning for the 1996 Reunion Weekend, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Event Planing for the 1997 Reunion Weekend, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript Arrangement and Description Manuals for Advanced Materials Characterization (AMC) Workshop, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Academic Assembly Presentation on Special Collections Overview, c. 1990 (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
- Miscellaneous Special Collections
  - Chronology and List of Staff for the New York State College of Agriculture, 1912, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Notes on the Jay P. Kinney Papers, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Olive Tjaden Papers, 1985, 1991-1992, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - List of Physics Collections, 1998-1999, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - List of Collections in Relation to Russia, Russian History, and Cornell University, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Carl A. Kroch Library and the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Miscellany
  - Building Plans for the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
  - Programs and Information Relating to Tours of Carl A. Kroch Library, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Text for the Carl A. Kroch Library Podcast, 1992, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Special Collections Group Minutes (Especially on Operations in the "New Building"), 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Drafts of the Carl A. Kroch Library Guide for the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Olin Handbook for Tours with Introductions to Manuscript Collections, 1989-1990, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Special Collections Surveys, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- The Charles W. Wason East Asia Collection and the John M. Echols Southeast Asia Collection
  - Articles in Relation to China, Chinese History, and Cornell University, 1905, 1968, 2002, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - China Central Television and the Hu Shih Papers, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence with Hu Tsu-Wang on Deposit of Rare Books, 1962, 1980, 1983, 1997, 2002, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 40-41)
  - Hu Shih's Graduate School File, 1913-1914, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Identifying and Cataloging Chinese Artwork, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - "Pink Slips" and Articles on the Wason (and Other Chinese) Collections, 1906, 2001-2003, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Wason Collection Paintings and Other Items, 2002, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence on Echols Collections, 1992-1993, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Cambodian Microfilm Project, 1908, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    Includes 4 Postcards Depicting a Guillotine Execution in Tonkin (Hanoi)
  - "A Report for Curators, Librarians, and Conservators," by Lisa Shekede; and Locked Press Items in the Wason/Echols Collections, 1987, 1990, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Echols Collection Coding Sheets, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Advanced Materials Characterizations (AMC) Training
  - Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Advanced Materials Characterizations (AMC) Manual for the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, 1984, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 50-51)
  - Technical Services Demonstration with Accession Flowcharts, c. 1984 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Techincal Services Work on Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Searching, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Searches for Special Collections Files, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 54)
- Documentary Heritage Program (DHP) Survey Reports and Advisory Committee Minutes and Planning, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- Lake Ontario Archives Conference, 1982, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Mid-Atlantic Regional Archives Conference (MARAC) Papers
  - Articles on RLIN Development at Cornell, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
  - Articles and Projection Transparencies on Automated Access to Records Relating to the Vietnam War, 1985, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - "Outreach: Get'em, Grab'em, Hold'em: From Net to Access" Presentation and Conference Program, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Program and Related Items for the Thirty-Seventh Rare Books and Manuscripts Section (RBMS) Pre-Conference, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- "Standard Elements for the Description of Archives and Manuscript Collections: A Report to the Society of American Archivists Task Force on National Information Systems", 1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Society for American Archivists (SAA) Conference Papers and Workshops
  - National Information System Task Force (NISTF) Paper on Standard Description Categories, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "Linking Accession Procedures and Descriptive Control," by K. T. Lynch; and, Correspondence for Organizing the Society of American Archivists (SAA) Conference, 1977, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Integrated Local Library Systems: Implications for Archival Programs"; and, Correspondence for Organizing the Society of American Archivists (SAA) Conference, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - "Integrating the Archivist: AMC, Local Systems and Archival Management in Research Libraries," by Thomas J. Frusciano, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Workshop on Effective Arrangement and Description, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Reformatting Images for Preservation: Digitizing Images at Cornell University", 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence for Organizing the Society of American Archivists (SAA) Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Workshop on Digital Imaging and the Kodak Library Image Consortium (KLIC) Project, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Pre-Conference Workshop on the Digitization of Photographs, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
  - Drafts and Projection Transparencies of "Metadata in the Digital Library: The Cornell Planning Process" Presentation, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Presentation on the Digital Access Coalition (DAC) and Tom Hickerson, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "What Was Home Economics? An Exhibition as an Onsite and Web Site Teaching and Research Project", 2001 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Automation Education and Information Advisory Committee Papers, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- "Data Elements Used in Archives, Manuscripts, and Records Repository Information Systems: A Dictionary of Standard Terminology," by the Society of American Archivists (SAA), 1984 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Papers and Correspondence for the Description Section of the Society of American Archivists (SAA) Steering Committee, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Descriptive Standards Proposal, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Society of American Archivists (SAA) Program Committee Papers
  - Program Committee Planning and Proposals, 1985, 1987-1988, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 31-38)
  - Program Committee Handouts, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Program Committee Proposal Forms and Conference Guidelines, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Program Committee Letters, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Society of American Archivists (SAA) Standards Committee Planning and Reviews, 1993, 1995, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 42-45)
- Publication Contract for the Case Study and Teaching Notes on "Developing Collaborative Structures for Expanidng the Use of University Collections in Teaching and Research", 1997 (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Review of an Archival Guide and an Archival Proposal, 1988, [n.d.] (Box 10, Folder 47)
- PowerPoint Presentations and Digital Image Collections on CD
  - Images of Robert Trent Jones Correspondence, Maps, and Miscellany, 2012; CD-2442 (Box 11)
  - "Regardless of Sex or Color" PowerPoint for Kendal Presentation and Cornell Women's Club of Syracuse Presentation, 2003, 2008; CD-2443 (Box 11)
  - Cornell Women's Club of Syracuse Presentation Images, 2008; CD-2444 (Box 11)
  - "Green Dragons and Big Red Bears: Cornell History and Traditions" PowerPoint Presentation, 2006; CD-2445 (Box 11)
  - "Jewish Life at Cornell" PowerPoint Presentation, 2005; CD-2446-2447 (Box 11)
  - "Part and Apart: Jewish Students at Cornell" Carol Kammen and Jewish Life PowerPoint Presentations, 2011; CD-2448 (Box 11)
  - Class of 1890 Photograph and presentation "Part and Apart: The Black Experience at Cornell, 1865-1945", 2011; CD-2449 (Box 11)
  - Cornell Club of Northeastern Ohio PowerPoint Presentation, 2008; CD-2450 (Box 11)
  - Images of Cornell University Library History, 2007; CD-2451 (Box 11)
  - Image of Ezra Cornell from John Reps, 2007; CD-2452 (Box 11)
  - Sample Digital Scans of John Flaxman's Illustrations for The Divine Comedy, 2007; CD-2454 (Box 11)
  - Photographs from David "Davy" Fletcher Hoy Celebration, 2008; CD-2455 (Box 11)
  - The Correspondent Breeze: Essays on English Romanticism by M. H. Abrams, 1984, 2011; CD-2456 (Box 11)
  - Doll House Photographs, 2005; CD-2457 (Box 11)
  - Highlights from the Andrew Dickson White Architectural Photographs Collection, 2002, [n.d.]; CD-2458 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Images from Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections for the Kodak Library Image Consortium, 1992-1993, 1996; CD-2459-2461 (Box 11)
    Kodak Photo CD Files (.pcd)
  - "600 Years of Urban Development and Planning," from the Wason Collection on East Asia and the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, 2004; CD-2462 (Box 11)
  - Howland Archives 1800-1900 and the Land-Sea Discovery Group, 2005; CD-2463 (Box 11)
  - Photographs from the Opening Reception of the "Vanished Worlds, Enduring People: Cornell University Library's Native American Collection" Exhibit, 2005; CD-2464 (Box 11)
  - Jessie R. Fauset Photograph, [n.d.]; CD-2465 (Box 11)
  - Introduction to George "Doc" Abraham's Africa Archives, 2007; CD-2466 (Box 11)
    Includes a Typed Letter from Chris Metzger
  - Tompkins County Public Library Charter Images, 2013; CD-2467 (Box 11)
  - Tom Hickerson Photographs, c. 1975, 1983-2005; CD-2468 (Box 11)
  - Hu Shih Papers Photographs, 2007; CD-2469-2470 (Box 11)
  - "Jewish Life at Cornell" Part Two PowerPoint Presentation, 2011; DVD-1477 (Box 11)
    StuffIt File (.sitx)
  - Photographs of the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, 2001-2007; DVD-1478 (Box 11)
  - "Jewish Life at Cornell" Pamphlet, 2011; DVD-1479 (Box 11)
  - Harold Saperstein '31, scrapbook items Phi Beta Kappa Society in the Class of 1931 Cornellian, DVD-1480 (Box 11)
  - Photographs of the Daniel Willard Fiske Museum in Grimsey, Iceland, 2009; DVD-1481 (Box 11)
  - Scans of the Cornell Chronicle, 1969-2007; DVD-1482-1485 (Box 11)
  - News Articles and Photographs of the Hans Bethe Tribute, 2005; DVD-1486 (Box 11)
  - "East Hill Notes with Gary Stewart: Show No. 202" Martha Van Rensselaer, 2009; DVD-1487 (Box 11)
  - Video from Professor Steven L. Kaplan's French 2270 - Versions of Versailles, 2011; DVD-1488 (Box 11)
  - "Ezra's Unreasonable Vision," by Frank H. T. Rhodes, 2007; DVD-1489 (Box 11)
  - Tom Hickerson Farewell Party Photographs, 2006; DVD-1490 (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous Buttons and Lapel Pins
  - College of Human Ecology Centennial Celebration Button, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - "Remembering Cornell" Advertisement Button, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - "Then. Now. Always." Cornell Reunion ID Button, c. 2013 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Cornell University Library Tour Gold Lapel Pin, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - "Preserving the Past" Lapel Pin, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Miscellaneous ID Badges
  - Cornell University ID Badge, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Cornell Migrant Program ID Badge, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Inauguration of Jeffrey Sean Lehman ID Badge, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Society of American Archivists (SAA) Conference ID Badges, 2008, 2011, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Kroch Sprinkler Project ID Badge, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - ID Badge with the New York State Seal, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Sesquicentennial Charter Day Newspaper Articles, Programs, and Miscellany, 2014-2015 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  Includes a Sesquicentennial Charter Day Button and Lance Heidig's ID Badge
- Newspaper Articles on the Fiftieth Anniversary of William Strunk Jr. and E. B. White's The Elements of Style, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 58)